Charles Puente-Matos

New York, NY 10017 - 631.988.0913

GitHub: /puentebravo | Portfolio: charliepuente.com | Email: puentematos@gmail.com |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/puentematos/

Full stack developer leveraging a background in creative writing to tell better stories through expressive applications. Specializes in TypeScript, React, and Python. Creative, laterally thinking engineer with a passion for leveraging the power of Artificial Intelligence to solve real-world issues.

Relevant Experience

Columbia University | New York, NY (Remote) | 2021- Present

Instructional Specialist, Full Stack Web Development

Responsible for aiding in the instruction of multiple 30-60 student online learning cohorts. In addition to assisting with class administrative duties, I take direct charge of a smaller group of students for in-depth learning, mentorship, and advising.

- Prepare the next generation of web developers via small group learning, pair coding, and one-on-one instruction 3 times a week during 5 hour classes.
- Study in demand frameworks and technologies to best prepare learners
- Maintain technical curriculum for quality and debugging to ensure an optimal learning experience

edX | New York, NY (Remote) | 2022 – Present

Tutor, Full Stack Web Development

Supports all edX Programming Bootcamps by privately tutoring students in need utilizing one-to-one mentoring, interactive lessons, and personal coaching.

- Improved learning outcomes for 6-10 students a week, strengthening understanding in a full stack curriculum that includes technologies across the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) Stack
- Create custom lesson plans tailored to a learner's needs and goals to further improve skills retention

Freelance Full-Stack Web Developer | New York, NY (Remote) | 2021- Present

Self-Employed Freelancer

Contracted to design, develop, and ship web modern web presences for private clients. Keep in daily contact with the client, updating them on the current state of the project while also making sure development is progressing in line with their vision.

- Utilize leading front and backend tools, libraries, and technologies to create sites that are both performant and accessible
- Tutor private clients in web development techniques, concepts, and basic skills

UK Department for Education | New York, NY (Remote) | 2022 – 2023

Teaching Assistant, Front-End Skills Bootcamp

Picked as part of an initial cadre of developers in carrying out a UK Government-funded pilot program to train Front-end engineers.

- Developed new SOPs and best practices for future course iterations
- Supported the growth of over 100 students across multiple time zones through pair coding, one-on-one mentorship, and on-call technical support

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, SQL, Python, TypeScript

Applications: Github, AWS, MS Azure, Gitlab, Docker

Tools: Node.js, Flask, Prisma, MongoDb, Jest, Express, React.js, GraphQL, LangChain, Django

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development Columbia University School of Engineering New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts, English Fordham University, New York, NY